<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="snowflake_connector.png"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Snowflake Connector</name>
    <shortDescription>Create a database connection to Snowflake.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node creates a connection to a Snowflake database using the selected Snowflake JDBC driver. 
            For further information about Snowflake see the <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/">Snowflake documentation</a>.
            <p>
            This node uses the selected driver's 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html#url_template">JDBC URL template</a> 
            to create the concrete database URL. Field validation in the dialog depends on whether the (included) 
            tokens referencing them are mandatory or optional in the template.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Connection settings">
            <description>
                This tab contains the main setting to connect to a Snowflake database. For more details about
                the different connection parameters see the 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/jdbc-configure.html#connection-parameters">Snowflake documentation</a>.
            </description>
            <option name="Database Dialect">
                Choose the registered database dialect here.
            </option>
            <option name="Database Driver">
                <p>
                Choose the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JDBC_driver">JDBC driver</a> to connect to the 
                database here. If you select "Use latest driver version available" upon execution the node will 
                automatically use the driver with the latest (highest) driver version that is available for the 
                current database type. This has the advantage that you do not need to touch the workflow after a 
                driver update. However, the workflow might break in the rare case that the behavior of the driver 
                e.g. type mapping changes with the newer version.
                </p>
                <p>
                If this option is not enabled, you can select a specific version of the registered drivers via the 
                drop-down list. Additional drivers can be registered via KNIME's preference 
                page "KNIME -> Databases". For more details on how to register a new driver see the
                <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html#register_jdbc">database documentation</a>.
                </p>        
            </option>
            <option name="Full account name">
                Specifies the full name of your account (provided by Snowflake). Note that your full account name 
                might include <b>additional</b> segments that identify the region and cloud platform where your account 
                is hosted e.g. xy12345.us-east-2.aws, xy12345.us-central1.gcp or xy12345.west-us-2.azure.
                <br />
                The domain <i>.snowflakecomputing.com</i> will be appended automatically to the full account name.
            </option>
            <option name="Virtual warehouse">
                Specifies the virtual warehouse to use once connected, or an empty string. The specified warehouse 
                should be an existing warehouse for which the specified default role has privileges.
                <br />
                After connecting, the 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/sql-reference/sql/use-warehouse.html">USE WAREHOUSE</a> command 
                can be executed with the <a href="https://kni.me/n/eh-RgddvYOj-B0uz">DB SQL Executor</a> node to set 
                a different database for the session.
            </option>
            <option name="Default access control role (optional)">
                Specifies the default access control role to use in the Snowflake session initiated by the driver. 
                The specified role should be an existing role that has already been assigned to the specified user 
                for the driver. If the specified role has not already been assigned to the user, the role is not 
                used when the session is initiated by the driver.
                <br />
                For more information about roles and access control, see 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/security-access-control.html">Access Control in Snowflake</a>.
            </option>
            <option name="Default database (optional)">
                Specifies the default database to use once connected, or an empty string. The specified database 
                should be an existing database for which the specified default role has privileges.
                <br />
                After connecting, the 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/sql-reference/sql/use-database.html">USE DATABASE</a> command 
                can be executed with the <a href="https://kni.me/n/eh-RgddvYOj-B0uz">DB SQL Executor</a> node to set 
                a different database for the session.
            </option>
            <option name="Default schema (optional)">
                Specifies the default schema to use for the specified database once connected, or an empty string. 
                The specified schema should be an existing schema for which the specified default role has privileges.
                <br />
                After connecting, the 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/sql-reference/sql/use-schema.html">USE SCHEMA</a> command 
                can be executed with the <a href="https://kni.me/n/eh-RgddvYOj-B0uz">DB SQL Executor</a> node to set 
                a different schema for the session.
            </option>
            <option name="None">
                Sending no credentials is required for some Snowflake specific logins such as SSO. 
                Please refer to the 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/admin-security-fed-auth-use.html#label-sso-with-command-line-clients">Snowflake documentation</a>
                for any further setup steps that might be required.
            </option>
            <option name="Username">
                Sending only the user name is required for some Snowflake specific logins such as key pair authentication.
                Please refer to the 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/jdbc-configure.html#using-key-pair-authentication-key-rotation">Snowflake documentation</a>
                for any further setup steps that might be required.
            </option>
            <option name="Credentials">
                If checked, the credentials (user and password) are used as defined on
                the workflow. The credential name links to the specified user and password.
            </option>
            <option name="Username &amp; password">
                Your log-in user name and password for the database. Note that the password 
                is encrypted before storage and decrypted afterwards for being used internally.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="JDBC Parameters">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define JDBC driver connection parameter. The value of a parameter can be a 
                constant, variable, credential user, credential password or KNIME URL.
                <br/>
                The <i>TIMEZONE</i> parameter is added with the default time zone of the KNIME runtime environment to 
                prevent mapping problems when working with 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/sql-reference/data-types-datetime.html">date and time data types.</a> 
                For more details about the parameter see the  
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/sql-reference/parameters.html#timezone">Snowlfake documentation</a> or
                ask your Snowflake administrator.
                <br/>
                The <i>application</i> parameter is added as default to all Snowflake connections to track the usage 
                of KNIME Analytics Platform as Snowflake client (for details go 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/jdbc-configure.html#connection-parameters">here</a>).
                If you are not comfortable sharing this information with Snowflake you can remove the parameter.
                However, if you want to promote KNIME as a client with Snowflake leave the parameter as is.
             </description>
             <option name="JDBC Parameters">
                For more information about the supported driver properties see the 
                <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/jdbc-configure.html">Snowflake documentation.</a>
             </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define KNIME framework properties such as connection handling,
                advanced SQL dialect settings or logging options.
            </description>
            <option name="Advanced Parameters">
                For more information about the supported parameters see the 
                <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html#advanced_tab">KNIME Database Extension Guide.</a>
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Input Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from database types to KNIME types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and database type will be mapped
                to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given database type will be mapped to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Output Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from KNIME types to database types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and KNIME type will be mapped
                to the specified database type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given KNIME type will be mapped to the specified database type.
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <dynInPort insert-before="0" name="Credential (JWT)" group-identifier="Microsoft Authentication">
            <p>
            To use this input port, you must attach the Microsoft Authenticator. Choose one of the
            OAuth2 authentication types and enter the custom scope you want to use. The scope is specific to
            the setup of your Azure Entra ID (formerly Azure Active Directory). 
            For further details on how to create a scope or where to find it see the 
            <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/oauth-azure.html#step-1-configure-the-oauth-resource-in-azure-ad">Snowflake documentation.</a>
            </p><p>
            When available the node will set the
            <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/jdbc-parameters.html#authenticator"><i>authenticator</i></a> as well as
            <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/jdbc-parameters.html#token"><i>token</i></a>  
            JDBC parameter automatically based on the information from the connected  Microsoft Authenticator
            node.
            Depending on your database setup you might need to specify additional JDBC parameters which are described in the 
            <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/jdbc-parameters.html#jdbc-driver-connection-parameter-reference">Snowflake documentation.</a>
            </p>
        </dynInPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="DB Connection">Snowflake DB Connection.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
